was way beyond anything I could ever imagine.
遠遠超出我的想像
I want to quit being a producer.
我不想當改造者了
For Nobuta to belong to everyone is painful for me.
要跟大家分享野豬對我來說很痛苦
I want Nobuta to be mine alone.
我希望野豬只屬於我
To be honest, I don't like anyone looking at her.
老實說，我不喜歡有人盯著她看
Yip yip.
嗷嗷
What the heck is he here for?
那傢伙幹嘛來啊？
He's totally ticked off too.
他一臉不爽
That hurts!
好痛
Let me just make doubly sure.
我再確認一次
You're really quitting being a producer for Nobuta?
你真的不當野豬的改造者了嗎？
Yes.
對啊
Then
那麼…
what do you want to do with Nobuta?
你想對野豬做什麼？
What do I want?
我想做什麼？
You want to confess your love and take her on a date to the zoo or something?
難道你想跟她告白 然後帶她去動物園約會嗎？
Yes, I'd like to do that too.
我也想那麼做啊
But what I want to do most of all is…
但我最想做的事是…
I'm not sure I should say this.
我不確定該不該說
Marry her.
跟她結婚
I'm so embarrassed!
好害羞
I knew it.
我就知道
He's gone way beyond anything I could ever have imagined.
這傢伙遠遠超出我的想像
The broadcasting club?
廣播社？
Aoi invited me to join it.
蒼井邀請我加入
That could be a good idea.
那樣也不錯啊
Sure, why not?
當然好啊
You'll meet more people too.
妳可以認識更多人
Club activities are so stupid.
社團活動好無聊
-Meeting people is such a pain. -It's perfect.
-認識別人也好麻煩 -很棒啊
I think it's really perfect.
我覺得非常好
Besides, I was thinking of taking a break producing for you.
此外，我在考慮暫停改造妳的計畫
Why…
為…
Why?
為什麼？
Well, you've made a friend,
妳交到朋友了啊
and if we're always hanging around you, you'll never achieve independence.
如果我們老是混在一起 妳永遠都無法獨立
-Right? -Right.
-對吧？ -對
Don't worry. We'll help you if you ever need it.
別擔心 有需要的話，我們都會幫妳的
Right.
對啊
And we'll figure out who's been harassing you.
我們會找出是誰在騷擾妳
Why the worried look?
為什麼愁眉苦臉的？
Don't worry about it, okay? It will be fine.
別擔心，好嗎？沒事的
I'll…
我…
miss you guys.
會想念你們
Don't be silly. We're in the same class.
說這什麼話，我們同班啊
We'll see you every day.
我們每天都會見面
This is stupid. I'll join the broadcast club too.
太愚蠢了，我也要加入廣播社
-Want to join too, Shuji? -What for?
-修二也要加入嗎？ -為什麼？
Okay! Avocado! A, E, I, O, U!
好了，麥克風試音，一、二、三
Love and courage are my only friends! Repeat!
愛與勇氣是我唯一的朋友，換妳
Avocado. A, E, I, O, U.
麥克風試音，一、二、三
-Avocado. A, E, I, O, U. -Good.
-麥克風試音，一、二、三 -很好
Love and courage are my only friends! Go!
愛與勇氣是我唯一的朋友，說吧
Hey!
喂
So today was…
也就是說…
the last day…
改造野豬計畫
of the Nobuta production project.
到今天為止
-Eight days a week, hello! -Hello!
-一週八天，大家好 -你好
The three of us will never do anything together again.
今後我們三人 不會再在一起做任何事了
These are new members, Kusano and Kotani.
他們是新社員草野和小谷
I'm Akira! Nice to meet you!
我叫彰，請多多指教
Nice to meet you.
請多多指教
Have a seat over there.
你們坐那邊吧
Today, we'll discuss our submission for the National Broadcasting Competition.
今天我們要討論 報名全國廣播大賽的事宜
I have a question. Are the sophomores going to submit something again this year?
我有個問題 今年也是二年級繳交作品嗎？
-Shuji! -Do you want to, Aoi?
-修二 -蒼井想試試看嗎？
Well, there are only two new members…
新社員只有兩位…
It's been ages since you last came!
好久不見了
Hey, let's really start raging with that song.
我們用這首歌炒熱氣氛吧
-You know. That one. -That one?
-就是那首啊 -那首嗎？
-That one. -Oh, that one!
-那首 -那首啊
This is so boring.
真無聊
Since when was karaoke so boring?
卡拉OK何時變得這麼無聊？
I'm worried about tomorrow.
我很擔心明天的事
Are we doing something?
我們有要做什麼嗎？
We're going to film something to play during lunchtime.
我們要拍攝午餐時段播放的影片
We are?
是嗎？
Yes. I'm not sure I'm the right person to be the reporter.
對，我不確定我適不適合當記者
You're the reporter?
妳要當記者？
Well, you're the assistant director, right?
你不是副導演嗎？
No, I'm not.
才沒有這回事
What?
什麼？
I'm the assistant director?
我是副導演？
You weren't listening at all, were you?
你真的完全都沒在聽啊
No way!
不會吧？
Okay! Whoever is the most ridiculous
好，最無理取鬧的人
gets the right to eat this last piece of melon.
就有權利吃最後一片哈密瓜
Most ridiculous?
最無理取鬧？
I mean, whoever throws the biggest tantrum wins.
也就是最會鬧脾氣的人就贏了
You're kidding.
你在開玩笑吧
Okay, kid. Do it.
好，孩子，去吧
Go.
去啊
Okay!
看我的
Dang it!
可惡
-Why the heck am I shorter than Watanabe? -Who's Watanabe?
-為什麼我比渡邊矮？ -渡邊是誰？
-Watanabe's a girl, right? -A girl?
-渡邊是女生吧？ -女生？
You sure have small dreams, kid.
你的夢想還真小，小子
Shuji, you throw a tantrum too.
修二，你也來鬧脾氣吧
-Yes. -What? Me?
-對啊 -什麼？我？
No thanks. I don't want the melon.
不用了，我不想吃那片哈密瓜
Come to think of it, you never threw a tantrum as a kid.
仔細想想，你小時候從沒鬧過脾氣
Really? You didn't?
真的沒有嗎？
I'm not sure why, but you've always been reasonable.
不知道為什麼，但你總是很講道理
Can I go then?
那可以換我試試嗎？
-You'll do it? -I want to see that!
-你要試嗎？ -好想看喔
I don't want to go to work!
我不想上班
I can't stand my boss!
最討厭部長了
Throw a tantrum?
鬧脾氣？
Being a liar is harsh!
說謊好難受
I don't know why, but it's so painful!
不知道為什麼，但真的好難受
It really is suffocating.
真的好難受
I'm now going to try…
我現在要體驗…
rolling noodles.
桿麵
I'm ready.
請多多指教
-Ouch! -Get to work!
-好痛 -開始吧
-Get rid of those kids out there. -Right!
-去趕走外面那些孩子 -好的
Hey!
喂
Shuji!
修二
-What's wrong? -With what?
-怎麼了？ -什麼？
You're not your usual self.
你跟平常不太一樣
You think so?
有嗎？
-Let's see some spirit! -Okay.
-打起精神來啊 -好
Tani! You're next.
阿谷，你是下一個
All right!
好
My usual self?
平常的我？
What is that?
是什麼模樣？
Is it like this?
是像這樣嗎？
This is the Sumidagawa High lunchtime broadcast.
現在是隅田川高中的午間廣播
It's Kotani! Kotani's on TV!
是小谷，小谷上電視了
-Can she even talk? -She's hopeless.
-那傢伙會講話嗎？ -不可能啦
-This is Towada Soba. -She's talking!
-這裡是十和田蕎麥麵 -她說話了
-Wow! She's talking!
-天啊，她說話了 -她在介紹
This is an old restaurant that's been around for 80 years.
這是一間有80年歷史的老店
Isn't it cute, the way Kotani moves?
小谷的動作很可愛吧？
Yes, it is kind of cute!
好可愛
Whoa! She fell!
她跌倒了
She tripped?
她絆倒了？
-I'm sorry! -That's so cute!
-對不起 -好可愛
Are you sure you want that much wasabi?
妳確定要加那麼多芥末嗎？
That's going to be way too hot!
太嗆了啦
Didn't I tell you?
我不是說了嗎？
-Kotani really is hopeless! -It's delicious.
-小谷真是沒救了 -好吃
She's having seconds!
她要吃第二碗了
Shuji!
修二
Kotani's on TV now. It's Kotani.
小谷上電視了，是小谷
Come in.
進來吧
-Come in here and watch! -Mariko! In here!
-快過來看 -真理子，進來看吧
Can I wait until this is over?
可以等我看完嗎？
That is all for Sumidagawa High's lunchtime broadcast.
以上是隅田川高中的午間廣播
This has been Nobuko Kotani reporting.
記者小谷信子的報導
That hurts!
好痛
-That was really great! -That was wonderful!
-太棒了
-Awesome! -Way to go, Kotani! You're awesome!
-做得好，小谷，妳太棒了
BROADCASTING ROOM
（廣播室）
That hurts!
好痛
Yes?
什麼？
I… You see…
我…喜…
I…
喜…
The aquarium was fun, wasn't it?
那次去水族館很好玩吧？
Shuji.
修二
Was I interrupting?
我打擾你們了嗎？
No, not at all.
完全沒有
So how are the club activities?
社團活動怎麼樣？
It's going all right.
還不錯
I saw the soba shop report. That was cool.
我看了蕎麥麵店的報導，很有趣
Everyone in class, they were applauding at the end.
全班的人看到最後都在鼓掌
I wish you could have seen it.
真希望妳能看到那一幕
That's all I wanted to say.
我只想說這些
Then why don't you go?
那就慢走不送了
Okay.
好
-Bye. -The exit is that way.
-再見 -出口請往那邊走
-Wait. -What?
-等等 -什麼？
There's a competition coming up.
之後會有個比賽
I don't know how I should film for it.
我不知道該怎麼拍攝
Yes.
對
Incidentally,
那我問一下
what's the theme?
主題是什麼呢？
Something that I like.
我喜歡的東西
Something you like?
喜歡的東西？
Let's go film it together sometime.
下次一起去拍攝吧
Good idea! Count me in!
好啊，算我一份
You're coming too?
你也要來？
You'd better believe it. I'm in this club!
當然囉，我都加入這個社團了
And the last number is three!
最後一個數字是3
-Three? -Yes!
-3？ -好耶
-We did it! -Yahoo!
-中了
We won the lottery? How much?
我們中樂透了？多少錢？
Three million yen!
300萬
-Three million yen! -Yahoo!
-300萬 -好耶
And including Head Teacher Sada, we split it five ways.
加上教務主任，五人平分
-That's 600,000 yen each! -Yes!
-一人有60萬 -好耶
-Mr. Yokoyama! Get the tickets! -Right!
-橫山老師，快去拿彩券 -好的
Get the tickets!
快去拿彩券
Okay! Calm down!
等等我
Three million yen!
300萬
Hurry up! Three million yen!
快一點…300萬
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
No way!
不會吧？
This is useless!
這樣就作廢了
Is this ball of trash 300,000 yen?
難道這團垃圾值300萬？
Yes…
是的
You're kidding!
不是吧？
So who's going to tell Head Teacher Sada?
誰去告訴教務主任呢？
What?
奇怪
Do you hear cicadas?
你們有聽到蟬鳴嗎？
There aren't cicadas this time of year. That's not a cicada.
這個季節沒有蟬吧，那不是蟬啦
An autumn cicada would be a huge scoop!
秋蟬是會是條大新聞呢
Delphine.
戴菲尼
What the heck's the point of a cicada living until fall?
蟬活到秋天有什麼意義呢？
You must be lonely!
你很寂寞吧？
Give it up, would you?
適可而止吧
Plop.
撲通
Nice!
很好
For both cicadas and humans, knowing when to give up is crucial.
不管是蟬還是人 懂得適時放棄是很重要的
May you go to hell.
下地獄去吧
Excuse me! What are you doing?
請問妳在做什麼呢？
I'm putting a curse on that damn Yokoyama!
我要詛咒橫山那該死的傢伙
-Putting a curse on him? -The lottery tickets we bought won.
-詛咒？ -我們買的彩券中獎了
Three million yen!
300萬
Really? Wow!
好厲害
But that damn Yokoyama washed the tickets with his laundry!
可是橫山那混蛋 竟把獎券跟他的髒衣服一起洗掉了
May he go to the grave!
去死吧
You can eat these.
這些你們可以吃
They've got ground shrimp in them.
裡面有包蝦泥
They're good!
很好吃喔
-You like it? -It's great!
-好吃嗎？ -太好吃了
The head is delicious.
頭的部分很好吃
-Good. -You're right!
-好吃 -真的耶
Yokoyama's head is great!
橫山的頭好好吃
Hear that, Yokoyama. You taste good.
橫山，你很美味喔
So you want to split up and film?
你們想分開拍攝嗎？
Then I'll go over there.
那我去那邊
Yip.
嗷
We're totally going to win first prize.
我們一定會得第一名
When do I give up?
我什麼時候會放棄？
Yes.
對
Anything is fine. It can be stupid. It doesn't matter.
任何事都行，很蠢的事也可以
I'm actually the kind of person who doesn't give up.
我是那種不輕言放棄的人
I mean, if you give up,
如果放棄的話
you'll regret it later.
以後會後悔的
What are you doing?
妳在做什麼？
Do you know Ishizaka?
你認識石坂嗎？
Ishizaka?
石坂？
A senior?
三年級的？
Yes.
對
Apparently, he likes me.
他說喜歡我
What? That Ishizaka guy does?
什麼？那個石坂？
He asked me if you and I were dating.
他問我們是不是在交往
I didn't know
我不知道…
what to tell him.
應該回他什麼
Are you and I a couple?
我跟你算是情侶嗎？
You should turn Ishizaka down.
妳應該拒絕石坂
He's got a really bad reputation.
他的名聲很糟糕
I heard he's always cheating on girls. I wouldn't--
聽說他經常腳踏兩條船，我不會…
Are you going to avoid the question again like usual?
你又要像往常一樣迴避問題嗎？
There's something wrong if you can't say if you're a couple.
不能對外說是情侶，不是很奇怪嗎？
It's not right.
這樣是不對的
The way things are, it's painful for me.
現在這種情況，我很痛苦
Isn't it painful for you too?
你不覺得很痛苦嗎？
Wait! You're filming the video for the competition?
等等，你在拍比賽的影片嗎？
Okay, go ahead. You can film me. Go right ahead.
來吧，你可以拍我，盡量拍
-Film me! -What?
-拍我 -什麼？
-Yay!
-好耶
Film me!
快拍我…
-Film me! -What's going on?
-拍我 -怎麼回事？
HIRAYAMA TOFU SHOP
（平山豆腐店）
Nice! They've got some really nice cameras nowadays!
太帥了，現在的攝影機真厲害
-First, let's look at Akira's. -Okay.
-先來看彰的吧 -好
-There. -Let's watch!
-開始 -來看看
What's this? The school?
這是什麼？在學校嗎？
I don't remember this place.
我不知道有這個地方
I bet you don't.
你不知道吧
This is cool.
太有趣了
It looks like a dog filmed this.
看起來像一隻狗拍的
Did you hear that? She said it's cool. All right!
有聽到嗎？她說很有趣，太好了
Next, Nobuta's.
接著是野豬的
Here goes.
開始了
His face is cut off, but that has got to be Yokoyama.
雖然臉被切掉了，但那是橫山老師吧
He's pulling up his pants, so it's definitely him.
看那個拉褲子的動作，就是他沒錯
This is hilarious!
太好笑了
-What are you filming?
-妳拍這個什麼意思？ -為何要拍這個？
-Darn you. Enough! -This is so silly!
-算了，別放了 -這太好笑了
What? You're going to give up on this?
什麼？妳要放棄嗎？
Yes.
對
-Then let's watch the next one. -Okay.
-那我們看下一段影片吧 -好
There.
好了
Nice!
太好了
Okay!
很好
You guys are at the peak of youth! Next…
你們正值青春年華呢，接下來就是…
Boom! Boom! Boom!
砰…
Boom!
砰
Okay? Oh, I'm too busy for this.
懂嗎？我太忙了，沒空搞這個
There you go. Sorry.
拿去，抱歉
-Next, my video. -Okay.
-接著看我的影片 -好
There.
好了
-Quit filming me! -Shut that off!
-不要拍我 -快關掉
-Film me! -It's dull and lacks rhythm.
-拍我 -無趣又缺乏節奏感
-You think so?
-快拍我 -是嗎？
It completely lacks surprise!
一點驚喜都沒有
It's dull!
好無聊…
It's cool.
好有趣
What?
什麼？
This is cool?
這有趣嗎？
It's really interesting.
真的很有趣
It's totally ordinary.
很普通吧
We should focus on a theme.
我們應該把重點放在主題上
Really?
真的嗎？
-Maybe so. -No, we don't need to.
-也許吧 -不對，才不是咧
I know it's pretty ordinary.
我知道這很普通
It's totally ordinary.
太普通了
Economy class level.
根本沒驚喜
Not at all.
一點都不有趣
What? Yes, it is. It's totally dull.
沒意思，超無聊的
All you've been looking at is what Shuji filmed.
妳一直看修二拍的影片
Yes.
對
Every time I watch it, I like it more.
越看越喜歡
Like? Like what?
喜歡？喜歡什麼？
Did you realize that he only filmed people?
你有發現他只拍人嗎？
What he likes are people.
他喜歡的是人
That's cool, isn't it? He looks so cold, but he likes people.
很有趣吧？ 他看起來很冷漠，其實很喜歡人
I bet he's the type who really cares for the people in his life.
他一定是個會真心 為身邊的人著想的人
For them, he's willing to lie
為了他們，他願意說謊
and he puts up with all kinds of things.
並且能忍受各種事
Watching this, I can tell.
看了影片後，我就懂了
I'll go and get my bag.
我去拿書包
There!
哎呀
Akira is down!
彰倒下了
I'm sorry!
對不起
-Are you okay? -I'm okay.
-你還好嗎？ -我沒事…
I'll go get someone!
我去找人來幫忙
I'm bleeding a lot.
我流了好多血
Sorry. You guys keep on going. Bicycle!
抱歉，你們先走吧，腳踏車溜囉
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
My fist… With my fist…
我的拳頭…
I heard she hit you with her fist.
我聽說她用拳頭打你
I was KO'd.
我被擊倒了
I'll buy ice.
我去買冰塊
I bet
我猜
it doesn't hurt anymore.
你應該不會痛了吧
It hurts.
好痛
My heart hurts.
我的心好痛
Well, when the girl you like punches you, I bet it does hurt.
也對，被喜歡的女生打一定很痛
I tried to
我本來
throw away the video that you shot.
想把你拍的影片丟掉
What?
什麼？
The video Nobuta worked so hard on to edit…
野豬很努力在編輯你的影片
I tried to throw it away.
所以我想把它丟掉
I'm a scumbag.
我是個混蛋
A total scumbag.
徹頭徹尾的混蛋
Smile, would you?
笑一個吧？
More.
笑燦爛一點
I wonder if I should give up.
我是不是應該放棄？
You've really become negative.
你變消極了啊
But I can't give up completely.
但我也沒辦法完全放棄
Do you really think
你真的覺得
Nobuta would hate you for just this?
野豬會因為這樣就討厭你嗎？
Do you?
是嗎？
I mean, surely you must realize that, right?
這種事你應該最懂吧？
But I'm a scumbag, man.
但我就是個混蛋
I'm a scumbag too.
我也是個混蛋
I really am sorry.
我真的很抱歉
No.
不
I'm the one who's to blame the most.
錯的人是我
But there was no reason to punch you.
但我也不應該揍你
You know what?
妳知道嗎？
When I found someone that I love,
當我找到心愛的人時
I intended to always live happily with that person.
我想和那個人永遠幸福地生活下去
But…
但是…
when you do live together…
如果真的一起生活
there will be
一定也會有
days like today where I'll end up making them cry.
像我今天這樣，把她弄哭的日子
I don't want to make them cry…
雖然我不想讓她傷心
but I guess I'll end up making them cry.
但我最終還是會弄哭她
Next is the video filmed by Shuji Kiritani and edited by Nobuko Kotani.
接下來是桐谷修二拍攝 小谷信子剪輯的影片
Go ahead, Kotani.
錄影帶給我吧，小谷
WHAT I LIKE
（《我喜歡的東西》）
All right. Fine. I give up.
好吧…我認輸
You can film me. Make me look good.
你可以拍我，要拍好看一點
Oh, the lottery? Yes, well. I gave up on that.
樂透？沒錯，我已經放棄了
I know it's too much to ask to make me look pretty. I've given up on that.
我知道要把我拍得漂亮 有點強人所難，我已經放棄了
As for marriage, I haven't given…
但我沒放棄結婚的…
When you give up, that means game over!
放棄的話就代表遊戲結束了
Isn't that right?
我說得沒錯吧？
Well, it's important not to give up.
重要的是別放棄
What about me?
我嗎？
Well, there are things I've given up on.
有些東西我已經放棄了
I'm still working on it!
我還在寫啦
"Give up on it this time."
“這次就放棄吧”
I gave up on that.
我已經放棄了
I'm actually the kind of person who doesn't give up.
我是那種不輕言放棄的人
You'll regret it later.
因為以後會後悔的
I can't give up completely,
雖然無法徹底放棄
but I'll give it up!
但還是得放棄
Rest in peace!
安息吧
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
But I can't give up completely.
但我也沒辦法完全放棄
You're going to give up on this?
妳要放棄嗎？
Yes.
對
Then let's watch the next one.
那我們看下一段影片吧
YOKOYAMA
（橫山，劇終）
What do you think of it?
你們覺得怎麼樣？
I liked it.
我喜歡
-Yes, me too. -I think it should be a candidate.
-對，我也是 -我覺得應該列入候選名單
You're right.
沒錯
Kotani, keep up the good work.
小谷，繼續努力
Okay. See you.
那我先走了
Bye.
再見
WHAT I LIKE
（《我喜歡的東西》）
Excuse me...
不好意思
That's the tape you edited, isn't it?
那是妳剪輯的作品吧？
Whoever did this knew it was Kotani's when they did it, right?
那個人知道這是小谷的作品 所以才這麼做吧？
Yes, probably so.
對，有可能
Are you all right?
妳還好嗎？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Why are you apologizing?
為什麼要道歉？
Never mind me.
不用管我
What bothers me is
我在意的是…
how people can express their feelings in such a cruel way.
怎麼有人會以如此殘忍的方式 表達自己的感受
You just can,
可以啊
when you're desperate.
絕望的人類就會這麼做
I did the same.
我也曾做了相同的事
Okay.
你來啦
I'm giving up.
我放棄了
What?
什麼？
I'm giving up on getting Nobuta.
我要放棄野豬了
Seriously?
真的嗎？
The right to be in love?
喜歡的資格？
I don't think you need the right to fall in love with someone.
喜歡一個人應該不需要什麼資格吧？
Yes, you do.
需要啊
You should never
讓女生哭
make a girl cry.
是不應該的
The way I am now,
現在的我
I don't have that right.
我沒有那種資格
I like Nobuta best when the three of us are together.
我最喜歡我們三個在一起時的野豬
I love her like that.
我最喜歡那樣的她
There's no school tomorrow, is there?
明天不用上學，對吧？
That's right.
對啊
Okay.
好吧
Then
那麼…
let's give up properly.
我們就徹底放棄吧
ON AIR
（錄音中）
Yip!
嗷
Nobuta!
野豬
I love you!
我喜歡妳
I love the books that Nobuta reads.
我喜歡野豬讀的書
I love the streets that Nobuta walks.
我喜歡野豬走過的街道
I love the roof where Nobuta is.
我喜歡有野豬在的屋頂
I love all the places where Nobuta is.
只要有野豬的地方，我全部都喜歡
I love them.
非常喜歡
So it is for Nobuta that I will now sing.
接下來，我要為野豬唱首歌
If on this ship I'm on
如果我乘著這艘船
I find your happiness
找到了妳的幸福
I'll be home right away
我會馬上回家
Won't you be my wife
妳願意當我的妻子嗎？
Why the heck is he singing?
他幹嘛唱歌？
On this moonless, desolate
在這個沒有月亮的荒涼之地
Dark night
漆黑的夜
Your smile
妳的笑容
Sings to me
對我歌唱
When you see the ship
當妳看到這艘船
Come running in your wet body
帶著濕濕的身體跑過來吧
This red ring of coral I made
我做了一個紅珊瑚戒指
I will give to you
要送給妳
If on this ship I'm on
如果我乘著這艘船
What is this?
這是什麼情況？
I'm not sure.
我不確定
What are you here for?
妳怎麼會來學校？
-Bye. -Yes.
-再見 -好
Even the waves are dreaming
就連海浪都在作夢
On the starlit night
星光閃耀的夜晚
Mariko!
真理子
You asked me
妳問我
if we really are a couple, right?
我們到底是不是情侶，對吧？
Actually,
其實
until now,
到目前為止
I've never been in love with anyone.
我從沒喜歡過任何人
So…
所以
I've never thought
我覺得…
that I love you either, Mariko.
我從沒有喜歡過妳，真理子
You see, romance and stuff like that,
像戀愛這種事…
I'm not comfortable around things that I can't control.
我不擅長面對那種 會讓人失去理智的事
I don't like them.
我不喜歡那種感覺
But
但是…
I wanted everyone…
我希望每個人
to think that I had
都認為…
a girlfriend.
我有女朋友
That's why…
這就是為什麼
I ate your bento lunches
我會跟妳一起吃便當
and stuff.
或諸如此類的事
Will it always be like that?
以後也是這樣嗎？
Is there…
有沒有可能…
a possibility that you'll ever fall in love with me?
你會喜歡上我呢？
No.
沒有
Sorry.
抱歉
Can it be fixed?
能修好嗎？
What?
什麼？
If we can get this tape all back in the cassette.
把帶子放回卡匣裡試試看吧
Nobuta…
野豬
Is something wrong?
你怎麼了？
I said something awful to Mariko.
我對真理子說了很過分的話
Starting tomorrow,
從明天開始
she'll probably hate my guts.
她可能會對我恨之入骨
You know…
妳知道嗎？
Being hated…
被其他人討厭
by others...
那種感覺
sure is terrifying.
真的很可怕
It's okay.
沒關係
Nobody
沒有人
will hate you.
會討厭你
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
對不起
I need to say something to Nobuta!
我必須跟野豬說點什麼
If I don't smile and say something, it will make Nobuta worry!
要是我不笑著跟野豬說點什麼 她會擔心的
Even though I thought that,
雖然我這麼想
I couldn't move.
但我仍呆坐著
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
After Nobuta hugged me, I, at last, realized…
在野豬擁抱我之後，我終於了解了
that I am…
我是個…
a lonely person.
寂寞的人
Who runs away when a friend is getting beat up?
朋友被打的時候，誰會跑走？
Shuji's a scumbag.
修二真是個混蛋
Wait a minute.
等一下
That's the kind of person I am.
我就是那樣的人
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻譯：黃雅婷